ILGWU. Leon Stein papers 5780/087
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. Leon Stein papers
1600-1997
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Leon Stein, 1912-
5780/087
16.47 cubic feet
16.4 linear feet
Records
Leon Stein's papers include draft manuscripts of Stein's own writings, several of Stein's unpublished manuscripts, drafts of Stein's translation of the work of Abrahan Cahan, research material for Stein's books on the Triangle Shirtwaist Factory fire in New York City and the Ludlow (Colorado) massacre, correspondence, and assorted clippings and printed material.
7128424
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff
Date completed:
June 2011
EAD encoding:
Cheryl Beredo, June 2011
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was founded in New York City in 1900 by mostly Socialist immigrant workers who sought to unite the various crafts in the growing women's garment industry. The union soon reflected changes in the sector and rapidly organized thousands of unskilled and semi-skilled women, mostly Jewish and Italian young immigrants. Exemplifying the "new unionism," the ILGWU led two of the most widespread and best-known industrial strikes of the early Twentieth Century: the shirtwaist makers' strike of 1909 in New York City and the cloak makers' strike of 1910 in Chicago. The union also tried to adapt to the fragmented and unstable nature of the industry. It adopted the "protocol of peace," a system of industrial relations that attempted to ensure stability and limit strikes and production disruption by providing for an arbitration system to resolve disputes.
The ILGWU exemplified the European-style social unionism of its founding members. They pursued bread and butter issues but provided educational opportunities, benefits, and social programs to union members as well. In 1919, the ILGWU became the first American union to negotiate an unemployment compensation fund that was contributed to by its employers. The ILGWU also pioneered in the establishment of an extremely progressive health care program for its members which included not only regional Union Health Centers but also a resort for union workers, known as Unity House. The Union also had an imaginative and pioneering Education Department which not only trained workers in traditional union techniques, but provided courses in citizenship and the English language.
David Dubinsky, an immigrant from Belarus who came to the US in 1911, provided strong leadership that led to unprecedented growth in the union during his presidency from 1932 to 1966. He led the union through successful internal anti-communist struggles, built on the ascendancy of industrial unionism by encouraging the formation of the Committee for Industrial Organization, and helped the union become an important political force in New York City and state politics, and in the national Democratic Party and Liberal Party as well.
In the period following the Second World War, the union suffered a decline in membership as manufacturers avoided unionization and took advantage of less expensive labor by moving shops from the urban centers in the northeast to the south, and later abroad. The ethnic and racial character of the ILGWU also changed as European immigrants were supplanted by Asians, Latin Americans, African- Americans, and immigrants from the Caribbean.
In July 1995 the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) at a joint convention, forming UNITE (Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees). At the time the new union had a membership of about 250,000 in the United States, Canada, and Puerto Rico.
Biographical / Historical
Leon Stein was born in Baltimore, Maryland, in 1912. After graduating from City College of New York in 1934, he worked as a cutter and patternmaker in New York City's garment industry, and became a full-time organizer in 1941. The author of many articles and books, Stein served as the Editor of Justice, the official organ of the ILGWU, from 1952 to 1977. He died at the age of 78.
Scope and Contents
Leon Stein's papers include draft manuscripts of Stein's own writings, several of Stein's unpublished manuscripts, drafts of Stein's translation of the work of Abrahan Cahan, research material for Stein's books on the Triangle Shirtwaist Factory fire in New York City and the Ludlow (Colorado) massacre, correspondence, and assorted clippings and printed material.
Conditions Governing Access
The ILGWU Records, except for publications and materials produced for publication, are restricted. Materials created prior to twenty years from the current date are open to researchers only with prior written permission from the Director of the Kheel Center; materials created during the past twenty-years are closed; the minutes of the General Executive Board are closed. For more information contact the Kheel Center.
Related Materials
5780. ILGWU records
5780/069. ILGWU. Leon Stein papers
5780/087 P. ILGWU. Leon Stein photographs
General
"Permanent deposit."
Women's clothing industry -- New York (State); Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State); Industrial relations -- New York (State); Stein, Leon,1912-; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
7128424
- Triangle Fire Interviews and Notes, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Triangle Fire Notes (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Triangle Fire Book Draft (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Triangle Fire Book Draft (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Letters, 1956-1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Triangle Fire Book Drafts (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Triangle (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Newspapers, 1938-1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Triangle Fire Letters and Research, 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- "W.I. Thomas and his Unfinished Jewish Study", 1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Scope and Contents
  by Rafael Schwimmer
- Wide Awake Library, 1881-1894 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Numbers 451 (August 29, 1881) and 1196 (March 31, 1894)
- The American Federationist, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  August
- The Big Shot, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  May 11
- ILGWU 40th Anniversary Convention, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  May 27-June 8
- "1882 The Year the Irish and Jews Staged new York's First Sympathy Strike on the Waterfront", 1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  In Justice September 1, 1969
- Justice 50th Anniversary, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Up to July 1900
- Garment Workers (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Bicentennial Issue of Life, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Notes and Letters, 1911-1939 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Notes and Bibliography about W.I. Thomas (Box 1, Folder 20)
- "Proposal for the Study of the Relation of Behavior to Social Structures in Scandinavia" (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Letters to the Editor of Bintel Brief, 1908-1942 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Letters to the Editor of Bintel Brief, 1906-1944 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Article, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  In Yiddish, October 3
- Articles and Handwritten Notes (Box 1, Folder 25)
  In Yiddish and English
- Letters to the Editor of Bintel Brief, 1906-1944 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Notes (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Letters, 1959-1966 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Drafts of the Germans Short on Time, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  October 20
- Article Excerpts (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Photographs [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Letters to Leon Stein, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  March 2-December 16
- Pamphlets, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Journey into ILGWU History and The Pipers' Guild Handbook
- Letters and Postcards, 1910-1967 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- 25th ILGWU Convention Report, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Letters, 1962-1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Articles, 1962-1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Photograph [folder removed to 5780/087 P], 1963 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  17-Jan
- Justice Newspapers, 1968-1976 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- "The Origin, Object, and Downfall of the Political Working-Men", 1829 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  in Albany Argus, June 8
- "U.S. Labor Editors Look at Israel", 1974 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- New York Council for the Humanities Annual Report, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Letters, 1966-1978 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- AFL-CIO News, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  March 23
- Fortune, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  January
- Triangle Fire Book Research, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Articles and Letters about Triangle Fire Book, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Newspapers and Pamphlets, 1964-1974 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Festival of American Folk life, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Chronicles News of the Past, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- "Plain Facts about the Working Women of New York", 1879 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Letters, 1957-1975 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Letters, 1969-1975 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Photographs [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Publications, 1966-1975 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Outline for "Working Americans" Exhibit at Festival of American Folk life, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Beadle's Dime Library Photograph Negatives [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Beadle's Dime Library, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- "Signature of 450,000" (Box 2, Folder 31)
  by the ILGWU
- Calendar, 1969-1975 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  January 1969-December 1975
- Calendar, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  January-December
- AFL-CIO Sixth Biennial Convention, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  May
- Photographs of Ludlow Colony [folder removed to 5780/087 P], 1913-1914 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- The Colorado Industrial Plan, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  By John D. Rockefeller, Jr
- Newspaper Clippings, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Articles on the Colorado War, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Interview Transcripts (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Harper's Weekly Articles on the Colorado War, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Articles, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Chronology Timeline (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Articles, 1913-1916 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- "Investigations of Coal Fields in Colorado and New Mexico", 1908 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  By the United States Geological Survey
- "John Franklin Shafroth, Reform Governor of Colorado, 1909-1913", 1952 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  By E.K. MacColl
- Colorado and Its People (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Edited by Leroy R. Hafen
- History of Colorado, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Prepared by the State Historical and Natural History Society of Colorado
- Lawson Case: A Brief History (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Issued by the Statistical Department of U.M.W. of A.
- Research Materials (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Photographs [folder removed to 5780/087 P], 1913-1915 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- "Militarism in Colorado", 1914 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- 'Songs of the Ludlow Massacre", 1955 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  Reprint from the United Mine Workers Journal, April 15
- Letter from James Lord to President Wilson, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  October 30
- Adolph Germer Papers, 1913-1914 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Ludlow Report, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  April 20
- Notes (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Map of Ludlow Station Surroundings, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  October 9
- Beadle's Dime Library, 1883-1903 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Letters, 1976-1984 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Interview with Leon Stein, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  March 8
- Letters and Handwritten Notes, 1908-1931 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Pamphlets of Triangle Fire Exhibits (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Triangle Fire Book Reviews, 1962-1965 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Triangle Fire News Clippings (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Triangle Fire News Clippings (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Triangle Fire News Clippings (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Triangle Fire News Clippings (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Triangle Fire News Clippings (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Letters, 1962-1974 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Articles and Periodicals, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  In English and Yiddish
- Notes (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Letters and Contracts, 1960-1974 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Articles about Triangle Fire Book, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Letters and Articles about Triangle Fire Book, 1962-1976 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Articles and Notes, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  In German and English
- Letters Between James O. Morris and Leon Stein, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Interview with Leon Stein (Box 4, Folder 7)
  By Joe Glazer
- Articles about Triangle Fire, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Letters and Travel Arrangements, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Newspapers, 1958-1964 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Photocopy Order Forms, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Letters and Contracts with Leon Stein, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Articles and Letters, 1914-1985 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Research, 1910-1985 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  In English and Italian
- Draft (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Articles, 1909-1914 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Letters and Certificates, 1935-1943 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Articles, Pamphlets, and Letters, 1984-1988 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Letters, 1967-1973 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Articles, 1911-1961 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Arts and Crafts, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Lili: A Saint Germain-Des-Pres (Box 4, Folder 22)
  children's book in French
- Articles, 1949-1981 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Letters and Research, 1955-1969 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- The Money Famine, 1888 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  By C.A. Blodgett
- Notes (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Notes (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Notes (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Notes (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Notes (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Notes (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Notes (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Notes (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Notes (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Drafts (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Drafts (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Drafts (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Drafts (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Drafts (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Drafts (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Drafts (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Drafts (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Interview with Triangle Fire Survivors, 1951-1958 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Drafts (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Drafts (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Drafts (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Drafts (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Three Feminist Bibles, Till the Cows Come Home, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Both By Leon Stein
- The Cloakmakers' Strike of 1910 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  By Abraham Rosenberg, Translated by Leon Stein and Meyer Miller
- Cahan Forward Eastside - Bintel Brief (Box 6, Folder 5)
- The Great Flanken War of 1902 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  By Leon Stein
- Abby Smith's Cows, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Leaves From My Life Volume III, 1926 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  By Abraham Cahan, Translated by Abraham P. Conan
- Pages From My Life Volume IV, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  By Abe Cahan, Translated by Lynn Davidson March 1968
- Drafts (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Drafts (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Drafts (Box 6, Folder 12)
- The Odyssey of Dr. Stiles by Leon Stein (Box 7, Folder 1)
- File on Fancy Dress Co. by Leon Stein (Box 7, Folder 2)
- "Outsiders and Unionists: The Progressive Response to Ladies' Garment Workers 1909-1910" by Henry L. Cohn, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Vassar College Department of History Thesis February 11, 1974
- Ludlow Colorado Photographs [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Personal Letters, 1962-1977 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Photographs of Leon Stein with Personalities [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 7, Folder 6)
- "The Sewing Machine in America", 1956 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  Reprinted from Charm Magazine
- AALC Reporter, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  August-September
- Draft (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Brochure for the Jefferson Lecture in Humanities, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  April 24
- Retirement Documents, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Articles (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Letters, 1975-1980 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  September19, 1975 - August 4, 1980
- Drafts (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Ludlow Map (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Jacob Stein Death Certificate, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  December
- Letters and Articles, 1917-1977 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Draft of Leon Stein's Trip to Africa, Israel, Germany, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  June-July
- Letters, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Photograph and Negatives [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Articles (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Personal Letters, 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Walter Stein Report Cards, 1953-1955 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- "The Immigrant Leon Stein" (Box 7, Folder 24)
- The AFL-CIO American Federationist, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  June
- Triangle Fire Photographs [Photocopies] (Box 7, Folder 26)
- "Wage Slaves" By Otto L. Bettmann, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Drafts (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Drafts (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Notes (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Ludlow Testimonies, 1913 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Ludlow Testimonies, 1914 (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Letters and Articles, 1964-1978 (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Colorado Coal Miners' Strike News Clippings (Box 7, Folder 35)
- Drafts (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Letters and Articles, 1963-1978 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- "Made in U.S.A. The Untold Story of Workers in America", 1979 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Articles, 1940-1978 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Photographs [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Letters and Articles, 1963-1978 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  In English, German, and Japanese
- "Ammons Tells Labor's Hosts of His Policy", 1913 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  The Denver Times, December 18
- "Military Despotism in Colorado" Pamphlet (Box 8, Folder 7)
- "75 Years of Banking Service in Southern Colorado and Northern New Mexico", 1950 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  Published by the First National Bank
- "The American Jewish Year Book 5702", 1941-1942 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  Edited by Harry Schneiderman, September 22 1941- September 11, 1942
- "Books on Women: A Catalog From Arno Press" (Box 8, Folder 10)
- "Proceedings of the Fifth Constitutional Convention of the AFL-CIO", 1963 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  November 15
- "Women in Science: Definitions and Data for Economic Analysis" By Carolyn Shaw Bell, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Photographs [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Letters and Articles, 1937-1977 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Newspapers and Pamphlets, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Letters, 1969-1980 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Pamphlet in Japanese, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Letters and Pamphlets, 1957-1981 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Pamphlets, 1907-1938 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Out of the Sweatshop Book Review By Richard C. Wade, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  In The New York Times Book Review, August 7
- Letters, 1976-1980 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- "The Ghetto in Litzmannstadt" by Bendet Hershkovitz, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Letters, 1970-1980 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Photographs [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Letters, 1967-1979 (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Articles, 1967-1978 (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Letters, 1953-1980 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Articles and Pamphlets, 1966-1980 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Photographs [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 8, Folder 29)
- Images and Photographs [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 8, Folder 30)
- Articles, 1911 (Box 8, Folder 31)
- Letters, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 32)
- Photographs [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 8, Folder 33)
- Letters and Articles, 1971-1975 (Box 8, Folder 34)
- Newspapers, 1970-1976 (Box 8, Folder 35)
- Articles, Pamphlets, and Letters, 1964-1980 (Box 8, Folder 36)
- Letters, 1974-1980 (Box 8, Folder 37)
- Photographs [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 8, Folder 38)
- Letters and Notes, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 39)
- Triangle Fire Book Review by Herbert Mitgang, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  In The New York Times School Weekly, April 8
- Triangle Fire Research (Box 8, Folder 41)
  Includes Photographs
- Textile Arts Textbook, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 42)
- Photographs and Images [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 8, Folder 43)
- Articles, 1941-1986 (Box 8, Folder 44)
- Musical Score for Mameniu, 1911 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  In English and Yiddish, Includes an Elegy to the Triangle Fire Victims
- Triangle Fire News Clippings, 1911-1985 (Box 8, Folder 46)
- Photographs [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 8, Folder 47)
- Triangle Fire Notes and Research (Box 8, Folder 48)
- Photographs and Images [folder removed to 5780/087 P] (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Triangle Fire Research (Box 9, Folder 2)
  Includes Images, Notes, Articles, and Letters
- Memoirs of a Cloakmaker Draft by Abraham Rosenberg (Box 9, Folder 3)
- "The Lock-out in the Cloak and Suit Industry", 1916 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  The Record of a Public Hearing, April 26
- The Cloak Makers' Strike, 1910 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  Issued by the Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers' Protective Association
- W.I. Thomas Draft (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Collection of Stories Draft (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Through the Needle's Eye Draft (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Cloakmakers Draft (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Notes and Letters, 1956-1958 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Draft (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Drawings by Henry Glintenkamp, 1911 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  March 11
- Newsletters, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Drafts (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Drafts (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Drafts (Box 9, Folder 16)
- The Odyssey of Dr. Stiles Draft (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Rosenberg Horn (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Draft (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Current Communications, 1975-1986 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  Includes Letters, Research, and Notes
- ILGWU Drafts and Research (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Drafts (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Memoirs of a Cloakmaker by Abraham Rosenberg (Box 10, Folder 7)
  Translated by Lynn Davidson
- W.I. Thomas and Bintel Brief Draft (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Sweatshop Draft (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Cahan Draft (Box 10, Folder 10)
- File on Fancy Dress Co. by Leon Stein, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  May 30
- The Education of Abraham Cahan Volumes I and II (Box 10, Folder 12)
  By Abraham Cahan. Translated from Yiddish by Leon Stein, Abraham P. Conan, and Lynn Davidson
- Articles, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  In Yiddish, April
- Articles, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  In Yiddish, May
- Articles, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  In Yiddish, September
- Article, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  In Yiddish, November 7
- Article, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  In Yiddish, December 1
- Article, 1920 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  In Yiddish, April 25
- Articles, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  In Yiddish, February
- Articles, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  In Yiddish, March
- Articles, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  In Yiddish, December
- Articles, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  In Yiddish, October
- Articles, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Articles, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Articles, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  In Yiddish, November
- Articles and Notes on the Theme of Mobility and Crisis as Related to Adaptation and Intelligence, 1912-1940 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Articles on the Theme of the Pattern of Wooing and Marriage of Convenience, 1912-1944 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Articles on the Theme of the Pattern of Wooing and Marriage of Convenience, 1906-1945 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  In Yiddish
- Articles, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Articles, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Articles, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  In Yiddish, June
- Articles, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  In Yiddish, July
- Articles, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  In Yiddish, August
- Articles, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 22)
- Articles, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  In Yiddish, January
- Articles, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 24)
- Articles, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 25)
- Articles and Notes, 1906-1927 (Box 11, Folder 26)
- Articles and Notes on the Theme of Ritual, 1906-1945 (Box 11, Folder 27)
- Articles on the Theme of Ritual, 1921-1945 (Box 11, Folder 28)
- Articles, 1913-1945 (Box 11, Folder 29)
- Articles and Notes on the Theme of the Role of the Editor, 1906-1945 (Box 11, Folder 30)
- Articles on the Theme of the Role of the Editor, 1907-1943 (Box 11, Folder 31)
- Articles on the Theme of the Role of the Editor, 1920-1945 (Box 11, Folder 32)
- Articles on the Theme of the Role of the Editor, 1914-1939 (Box 11, Folder 33)
- Articles on the Theme of Careers, 1914-1945 (Box 11, Folder 34)
- Articles on the Theme of Specific Jewish Problems, 1914-1945 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Articles on the Theme of Ethics and Law, 1914-1921 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Articles on the Theme of Proprieties and Refinements, 1914-1945 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Articles, 1913-1938 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Articles, 1906-1939 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Cahan Draft Volume 2, 1926 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Cahan Draft Volume 2, 1926 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Cahan Draft Volume 2, 1926 (Box 12, Folder 8)